A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1995-1996
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1995-1996
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.981
This collection consists of 35,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 1998 September 9.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by John Thomas Casteen, the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general files, 1995-1996; and,seldom-used permanent files, 1960-1996.
Organization
SERIES I: General Files, 1995-1996 Boxes 1-49
SERIES II: Seldom Used Permanent Files, 1960-1996 Boxes 50-83
SERIES III: Restricted Files, 1995-1996 Boxes 84-86
Contents List
- SERIES I: General Files
  - "A-Al" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - "An-Az" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--Law 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--General (3 folders) (Restricted) 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Admissions General--Medical 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - African American Affairs--General 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - African American Affairs--Woodson Institution 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association General--Board of Managers (4 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities--General 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education--General (1 of 4) 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education--General (2-4 of 4) 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Anthropology--General 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Applications (A-Z)--General (3 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Universities--General (4 folders) 1995 Jul-Sep (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities (2 folders) 1996 Jan-Mar (Box 5)
  - Architecture--General 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - Art--General 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - Arts--Planning and Development 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - Arts--Bayly Museum 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - Asian Studies--General 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - Assessment Planning and Studies--General 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - Associated Western Universities--General 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - Association of American Colleges--General 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - Association of American Universities (3 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Association of American Universities (1 of 3) 1996 Apr-Jun (Box 6)
  - Association of American Universities (2-3 of 3) (President Bill Clinton Photo in #2) 1996 Apr-Jun (Box 7)
  - (Box 7)
  - Association of American Universities (3 folders) 1995 Oct-Dec (Box 7)
  - Association of Governing Boards Advisory Council of Presidents 1995-1996 (Box 7)
  - Association of Governing Board--General (1 of 2) 1995-1996 (Box 7)
  - Association of Governing Board--General (2 of 2) 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges--General 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Astronomy--General 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Athletics--General (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 8)
  - Athletics--ACC 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Athletics--CFA 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Athletics--NCAA (3 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 9)
  - Attorney General--State General (1 of 2) (Restricted) 1995-1996 (Box 10)
  - Attorney General--State General (2 of 2) 1995-1996 (Box 10)
  - Auditor Internal--General 1995-1996 (Box 10)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts--General 1995-1996 (Box 10)
  - "Ba-Bm" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 10)
  - "Bn-Br" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 10)
  - "Bs-Bz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - Biology--General 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - Birdwood--General 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - Business and Finance--General (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - Business and Finance--General Updates 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - Byrd Leadership Award--General 1995-1996 (Box 11)
  - "Ca-Cg" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 12)
  - "Ch-Cn" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 12)
  - "Coa-Con" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 13)
  - "Coo-Cz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 13)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1995-1996 (Box 13)
  - Carr's Hill/Events--General 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Administration--General 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Cavalier Daily--General 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Center for Innovative Tech--General 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - City of Charlottesville--General 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Charlottesville City of Planning and Coordination Council 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Chemistry--General 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Classics--General 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Clinch Valley College--General 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - College of Arts and Sciences--General 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - College Board--General (1 of 2) 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - College Board--General (2 of 2) 1995-1996 (Box 15)
  - Commerce--General 1995-1996 (Box 15)
  - Community Colleges--General 1995-1996 (Box 15)
  - Comptroller (State)--General 1995-1996 (Box 15)
  - Condolences A-Z (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 15)
  - Congress--General 1995-1996 (Box 15)
  - Connie Lee 1995-1996 (Box 16)
  - Continuing Education--General 1995-1996 (Box 16)
  - Council of President's 1995-1996 (Box 16)
  - "Da-De" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 16)
  - "Df-Dz" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 16)
  - Darden Graduate School of Business Administration--General 1995-1996 (Box 17)
  - Development--General 1996 Jan-Jun (Box 17)
  - Development--General (2 folders) 1995 Jul-Dec (Box 17)
  - Drama--General 1995-1996 (Box 17)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) 1995-1996 (Box 17)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Economics--General 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Education--General 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Educational Testing Service--General 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Engineering and Applied Science--General 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - English--General 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Enrollment--General 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Enrollment Statistics 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Environmental Science--General 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Equal Opportunity Office 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - "Fa-Fh" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 19)
  - "Fi-Fz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 19)
  - Facilities Management--General 1995-1996 (Box 19)
  - Faculty--General 1995-1996 (Box 19)
  - Faculty of the Arts and Sciences 1995-1996 (Box 19)
  - Family Violence Prevention Fund 1995-1996 (Box 20)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1995-1996 (Box 20)
  - French Language and Literature 1995-1996 (Box 20)
  - "Ga-Gn" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 20)
  - "Go-Gz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 20)
  - General Assembly (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 21)
  - General Assembly Hoose Appropriations 1995-1996 (Box 21)
  - General Assembly Legislative Summaries 1995-1996 (Box 21)
  - General Counsel (1-2 of 3) 1995-1996 (Box 21)
  - General Counsel (3 of 3) 1995-1996 (Box 22)
  - General Service--State 1995-1996 (Box 22)
  - German--General 1995-1996 (Box 22)
  - Gifts and Grants A-C (3 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 22)
  - Gifts and Grants D-F 1995-1996 (Box 22)
  - Gifts and Grants G-K (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 23)
  - Gifts and Grants L-P (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 23)
  - Gifts and Grants Q-S (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 24)
  - Gifts and Grants T-Z 1995-1996 (Box 24)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1995-1996 (Box 24)
  - Governmental and Community Relations 1995-1996 (Box 24)
  - Governor's Office 1995-1996 (Box 25)
  - Governor's Office--Administration 1995-1996 (Box 25)
  - Governor's Office--Education 1995-1996 (Box 25)
  - Governor's Office--Finance 1995-1996 (Box 25)
  - Governor's Office--Natural Resources 1995-1996 (Box 25)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1995-1996 (Box 25)
  - "Ha-Hh" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 26)
  - "Hi-Hz" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 26)
  - History--General 1995-1996 (Box 26)
  - Honor System--General 1995-1996 (Box 26)
  - Housing--General 1995-1996 (Box 26)
  - Human Resource, Department of Key Advantage 1995-1996 (Box 26)
  - Human Resource, Department of General 1995-1996 (Box 26)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 27)
  - Information Technology--General 1995-1996 (Box 27)
  - Information Technology and Communication 1995-1996 (Box 27)
  - International Students 1995-1996 (Box 27)
  - International Studies 1995-1996 (Box 27)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 27)
  - Jefferson, Thomas Memorial Foundation 1995-1996 (Box 27)
  - Jefferson Scholars 1995-1996 (Box 27)
  - Jefferson Restoration Design Comm. 1995-1996 (Box 27)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 28)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 28)
  - Law--General 1995-1996 (Box 28)
  - Library--General 1995-1996 (Box 28)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous--General 1995-1996 (Box 29)
  - "M" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 29)
  - Major Events, Office of (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 30)
  - Management and Budget 1995-1996 (Box 30)
  - Marine Science 1995-1996 (Box 30)
  - Mariners' Museum (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 31)
  - Material Management (Purchasing) 1995-1996 (Box 31)
  - Mathematics 1995-1996 (Box 31)
  - Medical Center--General (1 of 3) 1995-1996 (Box 31)
  - Medical Center--General (2-3 of 3) 1995-1996 (Box 32)
  - Medical Center Health Science Council 1995-1996 (Box 32)
  - Medical Center Hospital--General 1995-1996 (Box 32)
  - Medical Center Medical School--General 1995-1996 (Box 32)
  - Medical Center Nursing--General 1995-1996 (Box 32)
  - Medical Center Personnel 1995-1996 (Box 32)
  - Music--General 1995-1996 (Box 32)
  - "N-Na" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 33)
  - "Nb-Nz" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 33)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--General (1 of 2) 1995-1996 (Box 33)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--General (2 of 2) 1995-1996 (Box 34)
  - NASULGC Board on Oceans and Atmosphere 1995-1996 (Box 34)
  - National Science Foundation--General 1995-1996 (Box 34)
  - New England Education Loan Marketing Corporation-General (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 34)
  - Newcomb Hall--General 1995-1996 (Box 35)
  - "O" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 35)
  - Oak Ridge Associated Universities--General 1995-1996 (Box 35)
  - "Pa-Ph" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 35)
  - "Pi-Pz" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 35)
  - Parking and Transportation--General (State) 1995-1996 (Box 36)
  - Parking and Transportation--General (University) 1995-1996 (Box 36)
  - Personnel and Training--General (State) 1995-1996 (Box 36)
  - Philosophy--General 1995-1996 (Box 36)
  - Physics--General 1995-1996 (Box 36)
  - Planning and Budget (State) 1995-1996 (Box 36)
  - Planning and Budget UVA--General 1995-1996 (Box 36)
  - President's Senior Cabinet Meetings-General (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 36)
  - Provost-General (4 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 37)
  - Provost Associate Provost for Research--General 1995-1996 (Box 37)
  - Psychology--General 1995-1996 (Box 37)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 37)
  - "Ra-Rh" Miscellaneous--General 1995-1996 (Box 38)
  - "Ri-Rz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 38)
  - Real Estate Foundation--General 1994-1995 (Box 38)
  - Recommendations A-Z (3 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 38)
  - Registrar--General 1995-1996 (Box 39)
  - Religious Studies--General 1995-1996 (Box 39)
  - ROTC--General 1995-1996 (Box 39)
  - ROTC Air Force 1995-1996 (Box 39)
  - ROTC Army 1995-1996 (Box 39)
  - ROTC Navy 1995-1996 (Box 39)
  - Rotunda Society--General 1995-1996 (Box 39)
  - "Sa-Sh"Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 39)
  - "Si-Sn" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 40)
  - "So" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 40)
  - "Sp-Sz" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 40)
  - Salaries--General 1995-1996 (Box 41)
  - Senate--General (3 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 41)
  - Sociology--General 1995-1996 (Box 41)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools-General (1-2 of 7) 1995-1996 (Box 41)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools-General (3-7 of 7) 1995-1997 (Box 42)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHEV)-General (6 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 43)
  - SCHEV Council Notes 1995-1996 (Box 44)
  - Student Council--General 1995-1996 (Box 44)
  - Student Council--Minutes 1995-1996 (Box 44)
  - Summer Session--General 1995-1996 (Box 44)
  - Student Affairs-General (1-3 of 5) 1995 Jul-1996 Jun (Box 44)
  - Student Affairs-General (4-5 of 5) 1995 Jul-1996 Jun (Box 45)
  - "Ta-Te" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 45)
  - "Tf-Tz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 45)
  - Treasury (State)--General 1995-1996 (Box 46)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 46)
  - United Way/Combined Charitable Campaign--General 1995-1996 (Box 46)
  - Universities Research Association--General 1995-1996 (Box 46)
  - University Journal--General 1995-1996 (Box 46)
  - University Police--General 1995-1996 (Box 46)
  - University Press of Virginia--General 1995-1996 (Box 46)
  - University Relations/News Office--General 1995-1996 (Box 47)
  - University Union--General 1995-1996 (Box 47)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 5) 1995-1996 (Box 47)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (4-5 of 5) 1995-1996 (Box 48)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1995-1996 (Box 48)
  - Virginia Festival of American Film-General (2 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 48)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review--General 1995-1996 (Box 48)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1995-1996 (Box 49)
  - "Wa-Wh" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 49)
  - "Wi-Wz" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 49)
  - Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service--General 1995-1996 (Box 49)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 49)
- SERIES II: Seldom Used Permanent Files
  - Administrative Duties--University Chancellor 1980 (Box 50)
  - Academic Plan (10 Year, Long Range) (4 folders) 1991-1992 (Box 50)
  - Executive V.P. (perm) 1974 (Box 50)
  - Athletics: Copeland, W. James, Jr. 1987-1995 (Box 50)
  - Ace Fellows Prog. III (4 folders) 1965-1994 (Box 51)
  - Architecture--Dean Search 1993-1995 (Box 51)
  - Armour II-Sup (3 folders) 1982-1991 (Box 52)
  - Athletics--Car Quest (3 folders) 1993-1994 (Box 52)
  - Athletics--Independence Bowl (2 folders) 1994 (Box 53)
  - Athletics--Peach Bowl (1995 December 30) (2 folders) 1995 (Box 53)
  - Athletics--Pep Band Letters (3 folders) 1993 Aug-Sep (Box 54)
  - Birdwood--General 1978-1991 (Box 54)
  - Carr's Hill (2 folders) 1960-1993 (Box 54)
  - Center for Advanced Studies--Gross, Paul (3 folders) 1986-1995 (Box 55)
  - Continuing Education--Nowlen, Philip M. 1987-1995 (Box 55)
  - Darden--Dean Search Committee 1992 (Box 55)
  - Development-Campaign (1 of 3) 1990 (Box 55)
  - Development--Campaign (2-3 of 3) 1990 (Box 56)
  - Development--Capital Campaign (3 folders) 1992-1993 (Box 56)
  - Development--Capital Campaign (3 folders) 1993-1994 (Box 57)
  - Development--Campaign Case Statement I (5 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 58)
  - Development--Executive Comm. II (1-4 of 5) 1993-1995 (Box 59)
  - Development-Executive Comm II (5 of 5) 1993-1995 (Box 60)
  - Development--Executive Committee (Campaign) (3 folders) 1993-1995 (Box 60)
  - Development--National Campaign Review Program I (5 folders) 1995-1996 (Box 61)
  - Development--National Leadership Gifts Council (4 folders) 1993-1995 (Box 62)
  - Selection--Campaign Consultant Meeting--1988 December 8 1988 (Box 62)
  - Education--Dean Search (2 folders) 1993 (Box 63)
  - Engineering and Applied Science--Dean Search (3 folders) 1994 (Box 63)
  - Enrollment--Growth/Expansion (1 of 3) 1990 (Box 63)
  - Enrollment-Growth/Expansion (2-3 of 3) 1990 (Box 64)
  - Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action Office VIII (3 folders) 1988-1993 (Box 64)
  - Equal Opportunity/AA - Director Search 1995 (Box 65)
  - Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action: Lewis, Lincoln V. (2 folders) 1987-1995 (Box 65)
  - Lawn Society-General (4 folders) 1976-1994 (Box 65)
  - Lawn Society--Meeting (2 folders) 1993 Oct (Box 66)
  - Lawn Society--Meeting (2 folders) 1993 Nov (Box 66)
  - Medical Center: Detmer, Don E. (1-2 of 3) 1987-1993 (Box 66)
  - Medical Center: Detmer, Don E. (3 of 3) 1987-1993 (Box 67)
  - Miller Center--General III (1-4 of 5) 1992-1993 (Box 67)
  - Miller Center-General III (5 of 5) 1992-1993 (Box 68)
  - Mingle, James J. (2 folders) 1989-1995 (Box 68)
  - Minority Affairs--Alumni 1986-1991 (Box 68)
  - Orientation and Training (Sup) (2 folders) 1990-1994 (Box 68)
  - Faculty - Retired (events) (3 folders) 1985-1995 (Box 69)
  - Fishback, William H, Jr. 1980-1995 (Box 69)
  - Founder's Day (1 of 3) 1993-1994 (Box 69)
  - Founder's Day (2-3 of 3) 1993-1994 (Box 70)
  - Garland, John 1993-1995 (Box 70)
  - Govenor Wilder's Budget Reductions (1 of 3) 1993 (Box 70)
  - Govenor Wilder's Budget Reductions (2-3 of 3) 1993 (Box 71)
  - Governor Wilder's Executive Orders 1990-1993 (Box 71)
  - Governor Bailes' Executive Orders 1985-1990 (Box 71)
  - Holland Scholars Program, Jerome (1 of 2) 1988-1993 (Box 71)
  - Holland Scholars Program, Jerome (2 folders) 1988-1993 (Box 72)
  - Thomas Jefferson Commemoration Comission 1993 (Box 72)
  - Real Estate Foundation (1-2 of 4) 1986-1993 (Box 72)
  - Real Estate Foundation (3-4 of 4) 1986-1993 (Box 73)
  - University-Related Foundation (2 folders) 1992-1993 (Box 73)
  - Sandridge, Leonard W., Jr. (1 of 3) 1987-1992 (Box 73)
  - Sandridge, Leonard W., Jr. (2-3 of 3) 1987-1992 (Box 74)
  - Service Awards (1-2 of 3) 1971-1994 (Box 74)
  - Service Awards (3 folders) 1971-1994 (Box 75)
  - Student Affairs-VP Search (2 folders) 1971-1995 (Box 75)
  - Senate Sexual Relations Policy (3 folders) 1993 (Box 75)
  - University of Virginia Foundation (5 folders) 1993-1996 (Box 76)
  - Visitors - Educational Policy Committee Meeting 1989 Nov 29 (Box 77)
  - Visitor - Brown, W.L. Lyons, Jr. 1988-1994 (Box 77)
  - Visitor - Bryant, Sean (Student) 1995 (Box 77)
  - Visitor - Butcher, Robert G., Jr. 1988-1992 (Box 77)
  - Visitor - Caplin, Mortimer M. 1993-1997 (Box 77)
  - Visitor - Connally, N. Thomas, M.D. 1989-1995 (Box 77)
  - Visitor - Elson, Edward E. (1 of 3) 1985-1995 (Box 77)
  - Visitor - Elson, Edward E. (2-3 of 3) 1985-1995 (Box 78)
  - Visitor - Hulvey, J. Thomas 1990-1994 (Box 78)
  - Visitor - Kluge, Patricia M. 1992-1993 (Box 78)
  - Visitor - Linney, Allison (Student) 1993-1998 (Box 78)
  - Visitor - Middledich, Leigh (2 of 2) 1990-1994 (Box 78)
  - Visitor - Scott, Buford 1987-1993 (Box 78)
  - Board of Visitors - General (1-4 of 5) 1993 Oct-1994 Dec (Box 79)
  - Board of Visitors - General (5 of 5) 1993 Oct-1994 Dec (Box 80)
  - Board of Visitors - General (3 folders) 1994 Aug-Dec (Box 80)
  - Board of Visitors - General (4 folders) 1995 Jan-Oct (Box 81)
  - Board of Visitors - General (4 folders) 1995 Nov-1996 Jun (Box 82)
  - Washington Papers 1976-1994 (Box 83)
- SERIES III: Restricted Files (Box Boxes 84-86)